安柏
Amber.
不好
No.
为什么
Why not?
安柏是脱衣舞娘的名字
Amber's a stripper name.
你倒是找个
Find me
叫安柏·哈蒂格的脱衣舞娘我看看
one stripper named Amber Hartig.
还是不要了
Or not, okay.
不用脱衣舞娘的名字  好吧
Non-stripper names, okay.
黛丝丽  斑比  坎迪金
Desiree? Bambi? Candy cane?
玛克斯
Max.
玛克辛
Maxine.
玛克斯·哈蒂格  很可爱  不是吗
Max Hartig is a cute name, isn't it?
如果是个职业拳击手的话  或许
If you're a professional boxer, maybe.
你能相信我们创造了这个小生命吗
Can you believe we made this little creature?
我知道  不可思议
I know, it's incredible.
这是我们做过最神奇的事
It's the most amazing thing we've ever done.
去年我差点就去跑马拉松了
I almost ran the marathon last year.
幸运的话  可别继承你爸的幽默感
If we're lucky you won't inherit your daddy's sense of humor.
你好  向小熊问好
Hello! Say hi to Bear!
她什么都没吃  怎么吐了
She hasn't even eaten anything, what is she spitting up?
亲爱的  我们不能再麻烦他们了
Well, honey, we can't bug them again.
可是
Just...
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
不好意思  这是我们第一个孩子
Sorry, it's our first kid,
可能我们都有点大惊小怪
we're both a little panicky I guess.
你下次得问儿科医生  我只是接生的
Well, you gotta ask the pediatrician next time. I just deliver 'em.
她吐了吗
She spitting up?
对  一个小时里第二次了
Yeah. Second time in an hour?
要是你在水下生活了9个月
You lived underwater for nine months,
也会吐不少东西的
you'd have a lot to spit up, too.
有什么问题吗
Is something wrong?
有点反应迟钝
Eh, a little lethargic.
我们不觉得...
We didn't think...
她很烫
She's hot.
她是...
Is she, uh...
婴儿在抽风  把急救车推来
Baby's seizing! Get the crash cart!
发生什么事了
What's happening?
什么  什么  什么事
What's, what's, what's, what's wrong?
我这里要人帮忙
Can I get some help in here?!
天哪  她没事吧
Oh, oh God! Is she all right?
要输液吗
IV access?
不  用氯羟安定
No, ativan.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
母性
Maternity
核磁共振结果出来了
MRI results are back.
然后呢
And?
和我们预料的一样
It's what we expected.
事故导致严重损伤
The accident caused serious damage.
失忆症
It's amnesia.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我只是无法相信
I just can't believe it.
来我们休息室享受啊  豪斯
Enjoying our lounge, House?
我来找点牛奶配咖啡  可你们没了
I just came in to get milk for my coffee, which you're out of.
矿泉水还是苏打水
Flat or sparkling?
-矿泉水  -苏打水
- Flat. - Sparkling.
哈蒂格家的孩子怎样了
So, the Hartigs?
孩子在发烧
Their baby gets a fever.
等等  别告诉我孩子还抽风了
Wait, don't tell me.Their kid had a seizure.
没错
Yep.
那对夫妇理所当然的会惊慌失措
The parents, of course, start freaking
我不得不花了一个小时对付他们
and I have to deal with that for an hour.
好像是你的错似的
Like it was your fault.
我接生的时候  她可是完好无损的
She was perfect when I delivered her.
要说责任的话  应该找儿科医生
If you want to blame someone,blame the pediatrician.
那么  小孩现在怎样了
So, how's the kid now?
肠梗阻  观察中  会好的
Bowel obstruction, she's under observation, she'll be fine.
这就成了儿科医生的功劳了
Pediatrician'll take all the credit.
展品A  女婴哈蒂格
exhibit A Baby girl Hartig.
顺产  出生42小时
Term baby, 42 hours old.
6小时前突发抽风
Went into seizures 6 hours ago,
送入加护病房
brought into the intensive care,
诊断为肠梗阻
diagnosed with obstruction of the small bowel.
我仍不敢想象你和病人待在同一个房间
I'm still amazed you're in the same room with a patient.
没长牙之前  他们不会很烦人
People don't bug me until they get teeth.
展品B  男婴豪森
exhibit B Baby boy Hausen.
也是顺产  出生48
Another term baby, 48 hours old.
在哈蒂格前被送入加护病房
Brought into the NICU before the Hartig baby:
不明高热  华氏101度  体温持续升高
fever of unknown origin,101 degrees, trending upwards.
太令人惊异了
Wow, that is amazing.
你整上午在妇产科休息室闲晃
You hung out in the OB/GYN lounge all morning
听到两个小孩生病了
and heard about two sick babies.
真可怕
It's eerie.
别碰
Don't touch that.
好吧
All right...
医院里有传染病传播
We have an infection spreading in the hospital.
这两个小孩的病完全没有关系
These kids have totally unrelated illnesses.
他们4小时内相继发病
They fell sick within four hours of each other.
同一产房
They had the same delivery rooms
产后病房相邻  传播完全可能
maternity rooms are neighboring,so transmission's possible.
他们有同样的症状
They have the same symptoms.
哈蒂格女婴是肠梗阻
The Hartig girl has a bowel obstruction.
无论他们的病床有多近
No matter how close their beds are,
我肯定  他们不会共享同样的梗阻物
I'm pretty sure kids can't share a blockage.
肠梗阻在病历上是什么意思
What does bowel obstruction on a chart indicate?
一般来说  我会说是
Well, normally, I'd say
表示病人的肠子有梗阻
it indicates a patient's bowel is obstructed,
不过我很肯定你有更高深的见解...
but I'm pretty sure you have some deeper truth to impart...
这表示  某某些无技术无责任心的医生
It means that some random doctor of indeterminate skill thinks
认为病人肠部有梗阻
that the patient's bowel is obstructed.
好吧  你不爽
Okay, you're upset
因为他们把你从休息室赶出来了
because they threw you out of their lounge.
看看X光片
Look at the x-ray.
是普通胀气
It's a normal gas pattern.
你要的话  我可以搞把肿瘤科休息室的钥匙给你
You want, I can get you a key to the oncology lounge.
是空气  直肠里有空气
Air. Air in the column.
我们休息室有录像机
We're getting TiVo.
如果是空气  就不是肠梗阻
If it's air, no bowel obstruction.
即便是空气
Even if it is air,
也可能是在肠梗阻前就有的
it could have been there before the obstruction.
不
No.
两个婴儿同时被感染了
Something's infected both these infants.
你是唯一一个把这两桩事联系起来的  因为...
And you're the only one who put this together because...?
因为我是唯一一个同时关注两个婴儿的
Because I'm the only one who looked at both kids.
我要求把他们隔离  并关闭产科病房
I want them isolated; I want the maternity ward shut down.
因为你比放射科医生更懂怎么看X光片
Because you're better at reading an x-ray than a radiologist.
放射科医生总是对婴儿的片子小题大作
Radiologists always over-read babies' x-rays,
特别是被要求排除病因的时候
especially if they're asked to rule out a pathology.
他们只看他们想看到的
He read into it what he wanted.
可你现在就是这样
Which is exactly what you're doing.
你在找他们的交集
You're finding a cluster
因为你觉得这很有意思
because you think it's interesting to find a cluster.
两个病因寻常的小孩会让你无聊的
Two... plain old sick babies would bore you.
看  这就是我不用花钱看心理医生的缘故
See, this is why I don't waste money on shrinks,
因为你就能免费提供全部深刻见解
'cause you give me all these really great insights for free.
心理医生
Shrink.
如果你打算看心理医生
If you would consider going to a shrink,
我会自掏腰包
I would pay for it myself.
看在上帝的份上  医院会举个行糕点义卖
The hospital would hold a bake sale, for God's sake.
医院有传染病蔓延
We have an epidemic!
两个生病的婴儿很不幸
Two sick babies is very sad,
但不能证明是传染病
but it doesn't prove an epidemic.
几个才够
How many do?
起来
Get up!
我们去打猎
We're going hunting.
猎什么
For what?
病毒
Wabbits.
你好
Hi.
再见
Bye.
他哭了  没事的
He's screaming, he's fine.
多漂亮的宝贝儿
Good looking baby.
对不起  走错房间了
Oh, sorry, wrong room.
回头见
We'll see you later.
12个病房  是吗
12 rooms, that's it?
没错儿
Yep.
我们检查了整层
We've definitely checked the whole floor.
好消息  没有传染病
Good news, no epidemic.
杯具啊  不是吗
Tragic, huh?
查查其他楼层的病房  3层
Overflow rooms, third floor.
这个想象中的传染病蔓延到下一层了吗
This imaginary infection has spread to the next floor?
我们正打算打电话
We were just going to call.
他是突然发烧的吗
Did he get hot all of a sudden?
是的
Yeah.
快到了
Almost there.
别担心  快到了
Don't worry, we're almost there.
打扰了
Excuse me!
-你好 -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
接待处让你们上来的吗
Intake sent you up here?
是的  我太太的宫缩少于...
Yeah, my wife's contractions are less than...
接待处搞错了
Yeah, Intake messed up.
我很抱歉  非常对不起
I'm very, very sorry.
阿尔普莱特护士会安排救护车
Nurse Alpret will arrange for an ambulance
送你们去普林斯顿总院
to take you to Princeton General.
妇产科临时关闭
The maternity ward is temporarily closed.
我们非走不可吗
We have to leave?!
是的  我很抱歉
Yes, I am very sorry.
为什么这么做
Why are you doing this?
你们很快就能到那里
You'll be there very, very soon.
现在满意了
Happy now?
不  不过我感兴趣了
No. But I am interested.
三个发病婴儿  第四个出现早期症状
Three sick babies, and a fourth showing early symptoms.
有多糟糕
How bad?
高烧
Spiking fevers.
血压下降
BP's plummeting.
几乎无法维持心脏收缩
They're barely able to keep systolic up;
照这个速度  一天之内就会死亡
at this rate, they'll be dead in a day.
婴儿来自哪里
Where did this come from?
2个产房  4个产后病房
Two delivery rooms, four different maternity rooms,
没有公共人员  没有共用仪器
no common personnel and no common equipment.
好吧  肯定有什么是共同的
Well, there's gotta be something in common.
没错  这就是传染病和巧合的区别
Yeah. That would be the difference between an epidemic and a coincidence.
我组织一队人  开始消毒
I'm putting a team together.We're going to start swabbing.
消毒什么
What's she gonna swab?
医院的每个呼吸器
Every respirator,
水槽  通风口  下水道吗
sink, vent, drain in the entire hospital?
要干上几个月呢
That'll take months.
大海捞针啊
A needle in a haystack.
比这还糟
It's worse than that.
我们都不知道要找的是不是针
We don't even know what's the needle we're looking for.
那你为什么还让她去做
Then why'd you let her go do it?
因为医院是她的孩子
Because the hospital's her baby,
孩子病了
and her baby's sick.
要是不马上解决  她会发火的
If she doesn't solve this soon, her head's going to explode,
我可不想被连累到
and I don't want to get any on me.
所以  让我们看看到底是什么
So let's figure out what's in the haystack.
鉴别诊断
Differential diagnosis, people.
寄生虫
Parasite.
传播的太快了
Spreading too quickly.
下一个
Next?
病毒呢
Virus?
孩子们病很重  验血也没有淋巴球增多
Kids are too sick, and the blood tests show no lymphocytosis.
而且他们对利巴韦林没反应
And they're not responding to a cycle of avirarapovirin.
如果是其他病毒  我们也无法及时找到它
If it's some other virus, we'll never find it in time, anyway.
所以我们应该考虑细菌性感染
Which leads us to bacterial infection.
孩子们对广谱抗生素没反应
It's not responding to broad-spectrum antibiotics,
因此是耐药菌株  比较常见的怀疑对象
so we've got something resistant.The usual suspects.
抗甲氧西林金黄色葡萄球菌  医院里总会有
MRSA. It's always MRSA in hospitals.
也许是污染的食物或者水源呢
Maybe a contaminated food or water source?
绿脓杆菌
Pseudomonas
抗万古霉素肠球菌
Vre?
H流感
H-Flu.
好吧  这些是可能性比较大的
Okay, those are the big ones.
细菌培养要48小时  估计他们死后才能出结果
Cultures will take 48 hours,might as well be post-mortem.
给他们用万古霉素治疗抗甲氧西林金黄色葡萄球菌
We'll start them on Vancomycin for the MRSA
用氨曲南对付其它的病因
and Aztreonam for the rest.
去做核磁共振  检查脓肿和隐性感染
Let's get MRIs, check for abcesses or some occult infection.
我会在门诊  有重大发现马上通知我
I'll be in the clinic. Grab me if you find something important.
不重大也行
Or unimportant.
我们给所有婴儿做了核磁共振
We did a MRI on all the babies,
不幸的是  一无所获
and unfortunately, we didn't find anything,
我们准备开始给他用最强效抗生素
so we're starting him on the strongest antibiotics we've got,
希望这能解决问题
and we're hoping that that'll take care of it.
不过他还这么小
But he's so tiny.
他的病有多严重
How sick is he?
他的体温是103.5度[华氏]  血压是80/40
His fever's up to 103.5 and his blood pressures 80 over 40.
很严重吗
Um, how bad is that?
这...
Ah, it...
血压很低
It, it's low.
心脏需要推动血液循环
The heart needs to circulate the blood.
如果心脏衰弱  氧气不会进到
If it's weak, oxygen isn't
肝脏  肾脏  和大脑
getting to the liver, the kidneys, the brain.
我想问你
Um, I have to ask you something.
朱迪...
Judy...
不  不  金  让我说
No, no, Kim. Let me.
我上个月得了感冒
Um, I had a cold last month,
我和医生说了  然后...
and I told the doctors about it, and...
亲爱的  这和你没关系
Honey, this has nothing to do with you.
金说得没错
Kim's right.
你儿子生下来的时候是健康的
Your son was born healthy.
他出生之后才被感染的
He caught the infection after his birth.
不可能是你传染给他的
There's no reason to think he got it from you.
不过你不知道  我是说
But you don't know, I mean...
你不知道他是怎么得病的
You don't know how he got sick.
相当标准的常见问题
Pretty standard question:
我孩子的病有多严重  你居然回答不出
how sick is my child? You couldn't answer it.
我回答了
I answered.
你只是飞快的说了数字  血压  氧饱和度...
You rattled off numbers! BP, O2 stats...
他们不想知道这些
That's not what they need to know.
他们想知道的是将要怎么样
What they need to know is the future.
难道你有魔力水晶球
Got a magic 8-ball?
不是  但我经过八年的医学训练
No, just eight years of medical training.
听着
Look,
我知道告诉家属坏消息很难
I realize it's tough to break bad news to family...
但比听坏消息简单多了
Not as tough as hearing it.
而且我想垂死挣扎是最难的了
And I guess being the poor guy dying is toughest of all?
不是
No.
自己死比看着别人死要容易
It's easier to die than to watch someone die.
我们正在检查通风道
Well, we're checking the vents,
疾病可能是通过空气传播的
it could be airborne.
谁去检查水槽  还有下水道
Somebody get the sinks, too,and underneath them.
我去
I'll get it.
你叫了多少医学院学生来打扫卫生
How many med students have you got swabbing the decks?
他们还能干什么
Oh, what else are they going to do?
他们又不在接生孩子
It's not like they're delivering babies.
发现什么了吗
Find anything yet?
有
Ah, yeah.
一半的洗手液器空了或者坏了
About half the antibacterial gel dispensers are empty or broken.
这很不好  但对诊断来说完全没用
That's bad. And diagnostically, completely insignificant.
如果员工不经常洗手
Well, if the staff can't wash their hands,
发生感染就不奇怪了
it's no wonder an infection has spread.
领带夹
Hey, tie clip!
什么
Sorry?
医院里正在流行传染病
We have an epidemic in this hospital
而你的领带却成为培养皿
and your tie is becoming a Petri dish.
戴上领带夹  或者把该死的领带拿下来
Put on a tie clip or take the damn thing off.
我的关节近来一直感觉很松弛
My joints have been feeling all loose,
而且最近一直身体不好
and lately I've been feeling sick a lot.
也许我运动太多了  我在跑马拉松
Maybe I'm overtraining;I'm doin' the marathon,
大概每天10英里
like, ten miles a day,
但我看上去一点也没瘦下来
but I can't seem to lose any weight.
举起你的手臂
Lift up your arms.
你有寄生虫
You have a parasite.
类似绦虫什么的
Like a tapeworm or something?
躺下去  把毛衣拉上去
Lie back and lift up your sweater.
把手臂放下
You can put your arms down.
你有办法治好吗
Can you do anything about it?
未来一个月之内有办法
Only for about a month or so.
一个月过后  拿掉它就是非法的
After that it becomes illegal to remove,
某些州除外
except in a couple of states.
非法的
Illegal?
不要害怕
Don't worry.
很多女人学会怎样和寄生虫亲密相处
Many women learn to embrace this parasite.
给它们起名  用小衣服打扮他们
They name it, dress it up in tiny clothes,
和寄生虫们一起玩
arrange playdates with other parasites...
一起玩...
Playdates...
他眼睛长得像你
It has your eyes.
但是  这是不可能的
But... that's impossible.
估计你最近没来月经
Well, I assume you weren't getting your period.
也许这对你来说是个暗示
Maybe that should have give you an inkling.
可我植入节育器了
But I'm on this birth control implant...
没错  我知道  我看见你手臂上的疤了
Yeah, I know. I saw the scar on your arm.
我的医生说  如果这个有效
and my doctor said I might
我也许一直不会有月经
not get any periods at all if it was working.
有意思
Interestingly enough,
它无效的话你照样不会有
you also don't get any periods if it isn't working,
所以你应该做常规怀孕测试
which is why you were supposed to get regular pregnancy tests.
我会叫个护士帮你做产前护理
I'm going to send a nurse in here to schedule your prenatal care.
五个月后临盆  你可以开始准备洗礼了
You're due in about five months,so start planning the shower.
医生  拜托
Um, Doctor? Please.
我和我丈夫很想要孩子
Me and my husband wanted to have a kid soon,
不过  天哪
but... oh, God.
四个月前我们大吵了一架
Like four months ago we had this really big fight.
他搬出去住了  我做了些傻事
He moved out.I did something stupid.
一夜情吗
One-night stand?
前男友
Ex-boyfriend.
那我会帮你安排一个亲子鉴定
I'll schedule you a paternity test, too.
我不能让我丈夫知道
I can't let my husband know.
你前男友长得像你丈夫吗
Does the old boyfriend look like your husband?
有点
Yeah...
那就把孩子生下来吧
Then just have the kid.
他不会知道的
He'll never know.
成功的婚姻是建立在谎言之上的
The most successful marriages are based on lies.
你有了一个很好的开始
You're off to a great start.
你们看上去很高兴
Well, you look cheery.
怎么了
What's going on?
哈蒂格和陈·卢皮诺家的孩子
The Hartig and Chen-Lupino babies.
他们的肾脏正逐渐停止工作
Their kidneys are shutting down.
尿液检查没发现管型尿
And the urine tests show no casts.
说明是抗生素造成的肾衰竭
Which means the antibiotics are causing the kidney failure.
你是肾病专家
You're the nephrologist.
哪种抗生素引起的  我们停用它
Which one did it? We'll take 'em off that one.
不要告诉我万古霉素和氨曲南都会...
Don't tell me both Vancomycin and Aztreonam can...
他们都会造成肾衰竭
They both can cause this.
没办法知道到底是哪种造成的
There's no way to know which one it is. No test.
我们不能停用抗生素
We can't take them off the antibiotics.
他们会死于传染病的
They'll die of the infection.
如果我们同时用两种抗生素
If we leave them on both the antibiotics
他们会死于肾衰竭
they'll die of kidney failure.
所以  我们只有尽力去猜测
So, we take our best guess, then.
哪种药引起了肾脏衰竭
Which drug's causing the kidney failure?
抗甲氧西林金黄色葡萄球菌是医院里最常见的感染
It's like I said: it's always MRSA in hospitals.
停用氨曲南
Take 'em off Aztreonam.
我仍觉得是绿脓杆菌
I still think it's the pseudomonas.
我支持停用万古霉素
I vote to take them off the Vancomycin.
猜测是没有用的
There's no point in guessing.
一个孩子停用万古霉素  另一个停用氨曲南
Take one kid off Vancomycin and the other off Aztreonam.
他们得同样的病
They have the same disease,
你却要给他们用不同的治疗吗
you want to give them different treatment?
你到底在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
通过治疗性实验来发现病因
Theraputic trial to find the cause of the infection.
这是不对的
That's wrong.
至少有四个孩子生病
We have four sick kids, at least.
谁知道到底有多少个还没出现症状的
Who knows how many more haven't started showing symptoms yet?
我们要对这两个孩子负责任
We have a duty to these two!
如果两个孩子有不同反应
If these two have different
我们就知道怎么去救别的孩子
reactions we know how to save the rest.
所以你是随机地让
So you're condemning one
其中的一个孩子去死喽
of these kids to die based on random chance.
大概是吧
I guess I am.
所以  你是要掷硬币吗
So, you're going to flip a coin?
你就是这么决定孩子生死的吗
That's how you decide which baby lives?
我可以借个硬币吗
Can I borrow a quarter?
你想被起诉  丢执照吗  豪斯
Do you want to get sued,lose your license, House?
照理说我很乐意你被起诉
Well, generally I'd applaud that,
但我的工作是保护这家医院
but my job is to protect this hospital,
所以我强烈建议你想出些医学理论
so I strongly advice you to come up with a medical rationale
说明为什么宝宝A用X药  反之亦然
why Baby A should get Medicine X and vice-versa.
我是在想这个  滑头
Whoa, whoa, whoa, hold on there, Slick.
我们可没上过法学院
We didn't all go to law school.
你的建议是我应该
Your advice is that I should
基于医学理论来做医学决定吗
use medical reasons to make medical decisions?
这可不简单
Hmm, that's not going to be as easy...
任何医学的合理解释
Any medical justification.
都不需要是完美的
Doesn't need to be a good one.
哈蒂格和氨曲南听上去都出自犹太民族
Well, Hartig sounds Jewish, so does Aztreonam,
所以哈蒂格家的孩子停用氨曲南  怎么样
so we'll take the Hartig kid off Vancomycin, how's that?
你不能在孩子身上做实验
You can't experiment on babies.
医生一直在病人身上做实验
Doctors experiment all the time.
是成人  并且要他们认可
On adults. With their consent.
好吧  我去征求家长的同意
Fine. I'll get the parents' consent.
你要告诉实情
Their informed consent.
他们必须了解  另一个孩子得到不同的治疗
They have to know the other kid is getting a different treatment.
抱歉  不能这样
Sorry, can't do that.
让一个病人知道
It'd be unethical for one
另一个病人的治疗过程是不道德的
patient to know about another patient's treatment.
他们有权知道
They have a right to know.
如果他们知道就不会同意  计划就失败了
If they know, they won't consent,that defeats the whole purpose.
这是他们的权利
That's their right.
又有两个婴儿出现了症状
Two more babies have just become symptomatic.
我会听从你的法律建议  哪个具有优先权
I defer to your legal wisdom:which takes precedence?
六个将死的孩子  还是一张失踪的医疗合同
Six dying babies or a missing consent form?
你不能这么做
You can't do it.
你觉得怎么好就怎么做吧
Do what you think is best.
你女儿的肾脏正在衰竭
Your daughter's kidneys are shutting down...
你儿子的肾快不行了
Your son's kidneys are failing.
所以我们打算给她停用氨曲南
...so we're going to take her of the Aztreonam.
我们要给他停用万古霉素
We're taking him off Vancomycin.
可是  最开始她是怎么得病的
But, uh, but what made her sick in the first place?
你们认为是什么东西引起的
What do you think is causing it?
看起来是一种叫绿脓杆菌的细菌
It seems to be a germ called pseudomonas.
我们认为是MRSA
We think it's MRSA.
抗甲氧西林金葡菌
Methicillin-Resistant Staph Aureus.
是一种常见的强力耐药菌
It's a very resistant form of a very common bacteria.
我们希望氨曲南可以治疗它
We're hoping the Aztreonam will clear it up.
万古霉素是治疗MRSA最有效的药物
Vancomycin is the best treatment for MRSA,
所以我们给她继续用这个药
so we're gonna keep giving it to her.
好的  这会治好她吗
Right. Is it gonna cure her?
您的孩子病得很重
Your child is very sick.
您得认清这个事实
You need to know that.
只能尽人事听天命了
This is a 'hail Mary' pass.
可能会治好她  也可能不行
It might cure her, it might not.
那  这能治好他吗
So, so that'll cure him?
如果有效的话  他24小时之内就会好转
We'll know in 24 hours if it's working.
你怎么跟她们说的
What did you tell them?
我把事实告诉她们了
I told them the truth.
她们看上去松了口气
They seemed relieved.
你说了他们的孩子病得多重吗
You tell them how sick their son is?
我跟他们说了现在的情况
I explained what was going on.
艾莉森  他们的孩子快死了
Allison, their baby's dying.
如果你离开的时候  她们没有泪流满面
If the parents weren't in tears when you left,
那你肯定没告诉她们真相
you didn't tell them the truth.
我不这么认为
That's not how I see it.
你想让她们一直蒙在鼓里吗
Do you want them blindsided?
等到她们嚎啕大哭  喊着
Want them coming up and saying
天啊  我的孩子死了  你怎么不早点告诉我
"My God, my baby died,why didn't you warn me?"
你是担心她们对我们大吼大叫吗
So now it's about worrying about them yelling at us?
不  我是觉得应该让他们
No, it's about getting them
为孩子的死做好思想准备
prepared for the likely death of their child.
如果明天她们的儿子死了
If their son dies tomorrow,
你觉得她们会在乎我今天说过什么吗
do you think they'll give a damn of what I said them today?
没有任何意义了
It's not going to matter;
他们才不会在乎
they're not going to care;
一切都会变得不同
it's not going to be the same ever again.
不过是给可怜的女人们几小时的希望罢了
Just give those poor women a few hours of hope.
豪斯医生
Dr. House!
天啊  不要
Oh, no!
豪斯医生  这是我丈夫  查理
Dr. House, this is my husband, Charlie.
谁告诉你我的办公室的
Who told you where my office was?
吉尔  很明显他不想我们打扰他
Jill, come on, he obviously doesn't want us bothering him.
躲还来不及呢
Ooh, I was trying to hide it.
医生  就是
Look, Doctor, this is
您说我得的那个传单(传染性单核细胞增多症)
about the mono you said you thought I had...
传单
The mono?
对  查理是不是也该检查一下
Yes. You know, shouldn't Charlie be tested?
你知道的  就是那个检查
You know, the test.
验血
The blood test.
没错
Right.
不好意思  我不太记得住病人
Yeah, I'm sorry, I sometimes forget patients,
我还以为你是那个不知道怎么避孕的笨蛋呢
I thought you were this idiot who doesn't know how to use birth control.
我不可能得传单
I can't have mono.
都没觉得恶心什么的
I don't even feel sick or anything.
初期通常没有症状
That's very often the first sign.
上午打电话到我办公室吧
Call my office in the morning,
我会安排他验血的
I'll schedule him for bloodtests.
太感谢了
Thank you!
我也没觉得全身无力啊
I'm not even tired.
查到什么了吗
Find anything yet?
没  就是池子里倒的奶粉
No, just some baby formula
堵在下水道口了
being stored under a sink with a dripping faucet.
自来水污染
Tap water contamination.
你觉得是绿脓杆菌感染吗
You thinking pseudomonas infection?
我以为是  结果浪费了几个小时来检查
I was. I wasted a couple of hours chasing it down,
这些奶粉当然得在婴儿附近
but of course the formula hasn't been anywhere near the babies.
不管哪个笨蛋把它们放这
Whatever idiot stored them there...
我们会查出来的
All right, we'll figure it out!
只是...  冷静
Just... just calm down.
我很冷静
I am calm.
我警告过你了
I warned you.
我做得很冷静
I did that calmly.
她好些了吗
Is she any better?
这几个小时里  她的烧已经退了
Her fever's been stable the last hour.
我们过不了这一关  是吗
We're not going to make it, are we?
什么
Sorry?
我和伊桑
Me and Ethan.
我们的邻居
Our next-door neighbor,
他们的儿子死于车祸
their little boy died in a car crash
大概葬礼的四个月之后
and she and her husband split up,like,
她和她丈夫离婚了
four months after the funeral.
世事如此  对吗
It's just, uh, what always happens, right?
病人离开医院之后发生了什么
Um, what happens to patients after they leave the hospital,
我并不清楚  尽量别太杞人忧天
I don't know, but... try not to get ahead of yourself.
奇斯医生  监视器有异常
Dr. Chase? Activity on the monitor.
多久了
How long?
我不知道  刚刚开始
I don't know, it just started.
脉搏多少  快速补液
Pulse? Fluid wide open.
我们插了动脉导管吗
Do we have an arterial line?
还没
Not yet.
先测下血压
Let's get a BP.
你不能进来
You can't come in here.
她要死了吗
Is my baby dying?
哈蒂格夫人
Mrs. Hartig...
她快死了吗
Is she dying?!
夫人  您得出去
Ma'am, you'll have to leave.
这不是你的孩子
It's not your baby!
人工通气
Ventilate.
血压60/20
BP 60 over 20.
心率180
Heart rate's 180.
注射左旋去甲肾上腺素(升压药)
They start the levophed?
已经注射了
They've got it.
血压还在降  50/10
Still dropping. 50 over 10.
三个加压器都不能维持血压吗
Can't hold BP with three pressers?
没有脉搏了
We're losing pulse.
室颤了
V-fib.
把帘子拉上
Shut the blinds.
充电
Charging.
闪开
Clear.
还是室颤
Still v-fib.
充电
Charging.
闪开
Clear.
充电
Charging.
闪开
Clear.
还是室颤
Still v-fib.
充电
Charging.
闪开
Clear.
充电
Charging.
奇斯
Chase.
死亡时间  下午6:57
Time of death: 6:57 PM.
氨曲南没用
The Aztreonam doesn't work.
把其它孩子的万古霉素用量加倍
Double-cover all the other babies with Vancomycin.
我去
I'll do it.
卡梅隆  你去通知父母
Cameron, you tell the parents.
告诉她们这孩子可能救了5条命
Tell them their child probably saved five lives.
不是该奇斯...
But Chase should...
奇斯很忙
Chase is busy.
你是主治医师
You're the attending.
帮助她完成任务
Make sure she does her job.
我叫你帮助她完成任务  不是你替她做
I asked you to make sure she does her job, not do it for her.
她都说不出话了
She froze up.
她同情那对父母  所以说不出
She felt sorry for the parents so she shut up.
你同情她  所以你就替她说了
You felt sorry for her so you opened your mouth.
她有心理障碍
She has a problem.
她得学会面对
Yeah, she needs to deal with it.
如果不是你帮她  她早就克服这障碍了
If you hadn't bailed her out,she would have done it.
那她也不会连睡两个星期
Great, then she wouldn't have slept for two weeks.
或许她该考虑换个专业
Maybe she should be thinking about a different specialty.
实验室  科研
Lab work, research?
怎么了
Yeah, what is it?
哈蒂格家的孩子
The Hartig baby.
病情也加重了
She's getting sicker, too.
万古霉素也不起作用
The Vancomycin isn't working, either.
万古霉素没用  氨曲南也没用
Vancomycin doesn't kill it.Aztreonam doesn't kill it.
到底是什么鬼东西
What the hell is this?
超级细菌
It's a super bug.
可能是抗万古霉素金葡菌
It could be VRSA.
整个美国
There's only been two
一共就报道过两个病例
reported cases of it ever in the United States.
那些孩子中有一个  豪森家的  有皮疹
One of the kids, the Hausen baby, had a skin rash.
可能是烫伤样皮肤综合征
It could be scalded-skin syndrome
是抗万古霉素金葡菌的体征之一
which would be a sign of VRSA.
那这些孩子死定了
Then these kids are dead.
这都是我们的错
This is our fault.
医生们开了太多的抗生素
Doctors over-prescribing antibiotics.
感冒了  吃点青霉素
Got a cold? Take some penicillin.
鼻塞  没关系  用点阿奇霉素
Sniffles? No problem.Have some azithromycin.
这些都没用了  那就用左氧氟沙星
Is that not working anymore? Well, got your Levaquin.
洗手间里全是抗菌肥皂
Antibacterial soaps in every bathroom.
很快我们就会往水里加万古霉素了
We'll be adding Vancomycin to the water supply soon.
是我们培育了这些超级细菌
We bred these super bugs.
它们是我们的孩子
They're our babies.
现在它们长大了
Now they're all grown up and
伤痕累累  满怀怨恨
they've got body piercings and a lot of anger.
另一方面
On the other hand,
许多抗生素都无法对付它们
maybe antibiotics had nothing to do with it.
你注意到最后他的血压特别低吗
Did you notice how low his BP was at the end?
即便上了三个加压器
Even with three pressers?
心脏损伤
Heart damage?
回家吧
Go home.
今晚你们什么都做不了了
There's nothing more you can do tonight.
男婴  陈·卢皮诺
Baby boy Chen-Lupino.
死亡时间  下午6:57
Time of death 6:57 PM
2004年12月2日星期四
Thursday, December 2nd, 2004.
这是陈·卢皮诺男婴的心肌横切
This is a cross-section of the Chen-Lupino boy's myocardium.
纤维化  淋巴细胞浸润
Fibrosis, lymphocydic infiltrates.
可是血液检查没有发现淋巴细胞增多
There was no sign of lymphocytosis in the blood tests.
对  我们都有理由相信这是细菌感染
Yes, well, we all had plenty of good reasons to think bacterial.
没人在责怪你们
Nobody is scolding you.
不幸的是  这些自以为是的理由都错了
Unfortunately, all of those clever reasons were wrong.
是病毒感染了他们的心脏
It is a virus infecting their hearts.
我们完蛋了
We're screwed.
我们不可能查出是什么病毒  可能性太多了
We can't chase down a virus;there's a thousand possibilities.
可以跑胶  用抗体实验
We could run gels, antibody tests.
做几千个吗
A thousand of them?
孩子们的血液不够
The kids don't have enough blood.
奇斯  你是这方面的专家
Chase, you're the intensivist.
在孩子面临死亡前  我们可以抽几次血?
How many could we do before we risk exsanguinating the kids?
是小瓶验血  不是针管吧
You're talking vials, not stick tests?
最多五六次
I wouldn't take more than five or six.
那我们得病毒范围从数千种缩小至六种
Okay, so we have to narrow the thousand viruses down to six.
尸检结果表明病因是病毒性的
Now, the autopsy's shown us what the virus does.
说吧  我们现在知道什么
So, let's go. What do we know?
三氮唑核苷和阿昔洛韦没有疗效
Ribavirin and encyclovir don't knock it out.
那就可以排除疱疹病毒
Cross out the herpes viruses.
也可以排除腺病毒
Also adenovirus.
还有呢  还有呢  接着说
What else, what else? Keep talking.
看来该种病毒只会危及孩子
Well, it, it only seems to hit children.
因为母亲们都没有异样
The mothers aren't sick, so...
排除弓形体病以及风疹
No toxoplasmosis, no rubella.
这就排除了TORCH综合症
Cross out the entire Torch syndrome.
有没有发现肺损伤
You didn't find any lung damage?
没有
No.
那就不是副黏液病毒科病毒
None of the paramyxoviridae.
记着  他们的心脏功能受损
Cardiac scarring, people.
巨细胞病毒呢
Cmv?
还有肠病毒
Enteroviruses, too, I think.
艾柯11型病毒
Echo 11.
甲型流感病毒
Influenza A.
甲流病毒
Influ A.
好  还有呢
Yes. And?
我把呼吸道合胞病毒也算进去
I'm putting RSV down as a yes.
现在有8种了
That makes eight.
抽8小瓶的血会有生命危险
Eight vials of blood is pushing it.
会有生命危险吗  可咱们爱做化验呀
Pushing it, but we love that!
去拿抗体试剂  着手化验
Get the antibody kits, start testing the sick kids.
那我去找找有没有抗病毒剂
All right, I'll start looking into
可以同时治疗这8种病毒
whether there are any antivirals for these eight.
等等  那些同楼层没有得病的孩子
Wait a second. The, the kids on the floor who didn't get sick.
还在医院吗
Are any of them still in the hospital?
他们被转移到五楼了
They got moved to the fifth floor.
不过现在应该都出院了
But they're probably all checked out by now.
没有  林德皮特家的孩子身上有些黄疸
No, the Lindpert boy had a bit of jaundice.
他应该今天出院
He should be checking out today.
把他的血液化验一下
I want to test his blood, too.
为什么
Why?
我们要获取尽可能多的信息
'Cause we need all the information we can get.
健康的孩子可以做对照组
The healthy kid can be our control group.
我去告他的父母说他们的孩子得了天花
I'll just tell his parents he can't check out
暂时还不能出院
because he has the smallpox.
好了  好了
All done, all done.
怎么样了
What did we get?
患病婴儿对艾柯11型病毒检测结果是阳性
Well, the sick babies all tested positive for Echovirus 11.
很好
Great.
还有巨细胞病毒和细小病毒B19均为阳性
And CMV, and parvovirus B19.
三种病毒的检测结果均为阳性吗
Three viruses?
更奇怪的  那个健康的孩子检查结果表明
What's weirder, the healthy kid we tested:
他对艾柯11型病毒
he's positive for Echovirus 11
和巨细胞病毒检测结果也为阳性
and CMV antibodies as well.
他们是新生儿
They're infants.
他们流淌着母亲的血  有着母亲的抗体
They have their mother's blood, their mother's antibodies.
难道我们一无所获吗
So we just learned nothing?
我们已经得到初步结果了
Uh-uh. We have half the picture.
健康的孩子得以存活
The healthy kids survived
是因为他们母亲的抗体救了他们
because their mothers' antibodies saved them.
如果母亲遭受过巨细胞病毒侵害
The mom had CMV in the past
她就会产生抗体
she'd have the antibodies for CMV.
那么孩子就会对该病毒免疫
The kid would be immune from it.
那我们该去检验患病儿童母亲体内是否有
So we test the sick kids' moms for Echovirus,
艾柯病毒  巨细胞病毒和细小病毒抗体
CMV, and parvovirus.
因此他们所没有的那种病毒抗体
And whichever they don't have the antibodies for,
就是他们孩子的病因
that's what's killing their kids.
我去化验他们母亲的血
I'll test the mothers.
艾柯11型病毒
Echovirus 11.
是一种肠道病毒
It's an enterovirus.
它寄生在肠道
It lodges in the intestinal tract.
肠道病毒会导致成人腹泻
Enteroviruses cause diarrhea
以及产生一些类似感冒的症状或是皮疹
and flu-like symptoms in adults, maybe a rash,
可该病毒对新生儿是致命的
but for newborns it can be deadly.
会损害她的心脏
It's damaging her heart.
你们打算怎么治疗
Well, is there anything you can do?
病毒感染比细菌感染更难治疗
Viruses are more difficult to treat than bacterial infections.
目前我们尚未发现普通感冒的治疗方法
We still haven't found a cure for the common cold.
那没有疫苗或者...
So, there's no vaccine, or...
宾夕法尼亚有家公司研制出一种抗病毒药
There's a company in Pennsylvania developing an antiviral.
实验结果表明它有良好的疗效
It got positive results in a lab setting and
而且我们已经拿到此药
we managed to get our hands on it.
试想若你无法触碰自己的孩子
Imagine not being able to touch your own baby.
能请你们帮个忙吗
Can I get your guys' help with something?
当然
Sure.
你们的女儿  她...
Your daughter, her...
玛克辛
Maxine.
那是她的名字
That's her name.
玛克辛
Maxine.
当护士换床单时
We need someone to hold Maxine off of the bed
需要有人把玛克辛抱起来
while the nurse changes her sheet.
好的
Sure.
福曼  有空吗
Hey, Foreman? Got a minute?
那两个孩子的肺血管阻力平稳
So, pulmonary resistance is stabilized for the two kids,
不过血压仍然...
but BP's still...
这不是新闻了
No news, then.
你怎么看卡梅隆
How's Cameron?
卡梅隆医生吗
Dr. Cameron?
是的
Sure.
先从她开始
Let's start with her,
然后再谈我们认识的其他卡梅隆
and move on to all the other Camerons we know.
抱歉  你关心他人
Sorry, I'm just not used
还真让我感到有些不适应
to you asking about someone's well-being.
我能理解对此你的惊讶
I can understand how the question would surprise you.
不过我不理解怎会让你困惑
I don't quite get how it would confuse you.
为什么你想知道
Why do you want to know?
为什么你想知道我为什么想知道
Why do you want to know why I want to know?
好奇而已
Just curious.
我也是
Me, too.
你没有好奇心
You don't get curious.
我是这个世界上好奇心最强的人
I'm the most curious man in the world.
可你对日常琐事不好奇
Not about trivialities.
这当然不是日常琐事
Well, then, this must not be trivial.
卡梅隆的处事能力如何
How is Cameron handling everything?
挺好的
Just fine.
很好  我知道了
Great, glad we talked.
是你老公给你种的"传单"(怀孕)
Your husband is definitely the source of your "Mono".
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
我要当妈妈了
Wow, I'm going to be a mom.
太谢谢你了
Thank you so much;
我得给你买个礼物之类的来感谢你
I gotta get you a gift or something.
最好的礼物就是以后都看不见你
Sometimes the best gift is the gift of never seeing you again.
好的
Okay, all right!
豪斯医生  你太牛了
But, Dr. House, you've been so awesome.
我真的十分信任你
I mean, I really, totally trust you.
你能不能...
Do you think you...
不
No.
帮我做产前
...could do the prenatal?
-不  -那替我接生呢
- No.  - Or deliver the baby?
答案是不行
That would be no.
好吧
Okay!
奇斯  看看这个
Chase, take a look at this.
天哪  是好消息
Oh, God. It's good news.
不  是天大的好消息
No, it's great.
她恢复的很好
She's doing great.
他们都走了吗
They all gone?
哈蒂格家正在办理出院手续
Hartigs are checking out right now.
你看起来很疲倦
You look tired.
多谢关心
Thanks.
这也难怪
It's no wonder.
过去的这段日子你过于操劳
You've had a hard time the last couple of days.
难道你没有吗
And you haven't?
跟你不一样
Not like you.
行为举止如此怪异的人
Anyone who's that awkward
要么没有经历过生离死别
either has no experience with death
要么就是经历了太多
or too much,
我确信不是前者
and I'm pretty sure it's not the former.
奇斯说让父母抱着孩子
Chase told me about that idea you had:
是你的主意
the parents holding the baby.
你怎么想到的
Where'd you get that?
你是不是失去过某人
Did you lose someone?
一个孩子吗
Did you lose a baby?
你真是个混蛋
You can be a real bastard.
还没完吗
Unfinished business?
我很迷茫
I'm in the haystack.
因为你知道你是在大海捞针
Ah, because now you know you're looking for a needle.
是的
Right.
即便我说"随它去吧"
If I tell you to "Let it go,"
也没什么用吧
it won't make any difference, will it?
肠道病毒通过人体传播
Enteroviruses are spread by humans.
通常是粪便或者唾液
Fecal, oral usually...
也可能是呼吸道分泌物
could be respiratory secretions, though.
因此卡迪取了全院职工的粪便样本
So, Cuddy got stool samples from the whole staff.
现在只等化验结果
Just wait until they come back.
-没用的  -为什么
- That won't do it.  - Why not?
无论传播者是谁
The shedder, whoever he is,
他都应该极具毒性  会伴随有一些症状
is so virulent, he must have been symptomatic.
卡迪会注意到他的
Cuddy would have noticed him.
况且普通职工也无法触及这些孩子
And the babies didn't share any common personnel.
这就是诡异之处
That's what's weird.
是啊  是啊  真的很诡异
Yeah, yeah. That's what's weird.
有事吗
Can I help you?
你救了我一命
You saved my life.
我只是帮你做了些检查而已
I just ran some tests.
是你的求生意志救了你
Your will and determination are what saved your life.
我知道我是谁
I know who I am now.
是的
Yes, you do.
我也清楚自己的身份
And I know who I am as well.
说真的  你不该待在这里
Hey, seriously, man, you're not supposed to be here.
我在演习如何接生
I'm performing a delivery.
你帮人接生吗
You are.
我接手了病人的产前护理
Patient whose prenatal care I've been handling.
几分钟前她刚离开医院
Just checking her out a couple of minutes ago.
当然接生时我需要你们中的一人协助我
Of course, I'll need one of you two guys to supervise.
她的预产期是什么时候
When's she due?
三月底
Late March.
那是五个月以后
That's five months from now.
幸亏这些椅子够舒服
Thank God these chairs are comfortable.